curriki.org 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy | Curriki

Effective: May 31, 2018

At Curriki, we provide educators, including pre-service and new teachers, and parents with open educational resources and tools to improve student achievement across the board. In this privacy policy, we tell you what information we receive from you when you use Curriki and how we use it to continue to improve our services.

 **Scope of this Privacy Policy**

Curriki (“Curriki,” “we,” “our,” and/or “us”) values your privacy. This privacy policy governs all of types of data we collect through the Services. It explains what information we collect, use, and share in connection with our website at www.curriki.org (the “Services”). Please take the time to familiarize yourself with our policies. Your use of the Services is also governed by Curriki’s Terms of Use.

 **Information We Collect**

 _Registration Information_

When you register for the services, you provide personal information, such as your name, email address, city, state, zip code, and gender. You can also register for Curriki through or otherwise grant access to a third party social networking or authentication service, such as Facebook or Google, we will receive information from that service such as your name, email address, and other information you may make available via the service. You can manage what information you share with us through such services by updating your preferences through those services.

If you sign up to receive newsletters or other communications from us or otherwise contact us, you may also provide us with your name, email address, role or position, country, and information about your interests.

We do not verify users’ identities before collecting personal information. Please note that we do not offer different classes of user accounts or managed accounts for educators, parents, or others.

 _Profile and Contributions_

Once you register for the Services, you may fill out an account profile. We receive any profile information that you provide including your bio, photograph, organization, language, and interests; links to your social media pages, websites, or blogs; and community Contributions. Contributions include posting resources to your profile or groups, posting information on forums, and providing reviews of resources other users post. We also collect information about which friends you are following, groups you have joined, and resources you have saved to your library on our Services. Curriki (not a third party) receives and stores this user content. When you choose to add or upload this information to the Services, we do not seek any additional opt-in consent before storing this information.

 _Donations_

You can make donations to us online through our payment vendors. When you make an online donation, we do not receive or store your payment information, but we will receive your name, mailing address, email address, and donation amount based on the form you fill out. If you make an offline donation, we receive your name, mailing address, email address, donation amount, and payment information, but we do not store or process credit card information.

 _Log Files_

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (“IP”) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (“ISP”), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and your use of our Services.

We use this information, on an aggregated, de-identified basis, to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ movements around the site, and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

 _Cookies_

When you visit our homepage, we provide notice that our website uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use both session cookies and/or persistent cookies. A session cookie expires when you close your browser. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.

A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. We set a persistent cookie for authentication purposes. We use persistent cookies to collect behavioral data, i.e., information about your interests as you browse the web. We use this information to enhance your experience on our site. We also use analytics providers such as Google Analytics who use cookies for analytics purposes. You can find more information on how Google uses data from these cookies at google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. These analytics providers may collect or have access to information about you which they may collect over time and across different websites.

You can make decisions about cookies through your browser settings. If your web browser rejects cookies, you may still use our Services, but your ability to use some areas of our Services may be limited.

 _Combining Information_

If we combine any information with your personal information, such as your registration information, we will treat all of that information as personal information.

 _Information We Don’t Collect_

We limit our collection of information to only data that are necessary to provide or help improve the Services. We do not receive information about users from any third parties, or combine, augment, extend the information that we collect with data from third party sources. We do not collect sensitive information such as health, financial, biometric, or geolocation data on the Services. Because the Services are directed to teachers and parents, we also do not knowingly collect personal information (including educational records and information about free or reduced lunch status) from preschool or K-12 students or children under the age of 12. Please see the section on Children’s Information below for more information.

 **How We Use the Information We Collect**

We use your information only for the educational purposes for which we collect it in the following ways:

· Provide, improve, personalize, and promote the Services;  
· Develop new services, features, and functionality;  
· Communicate with you, such as to respond to your comments, questions, and requests; provide customer service and support; and provide you with information about the Services, donation opportunities, administrative and marketing messages, and other news or information about us;  
· Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with the Services; and  
· Investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions, unauthorized access to the Services, and other illegal activities.

We may de-identify or aggregate data collected through the Services using industry standards and best practices, and use and disclose it for any purpose.

 **How We Share the Information We Collect**

 _Contributions_

All Contributions you make on the site are linked to your user profile and user name. Any member of the site and the general public on the Internet (“the public”) can view your profile and the  
information stored there including all of your published contributions (but not your unpublished contributions). You can choose to keep your email address private, but all users and the public can see your published Contributions and that your user name is associated with the Contribution. While we may make available certain privacy settings for your profile, we cannot guarantee that information you provide us will not be accessible by third parties.

 _Other Users and the Public_

Curriki is a service dedicated to supporting learning communities. Your profile and any comments, resources, content, and information you submit to the public areas of the Services, such as the forums, can be read, collected, or used by other users and the public. We are not responsible for the information you choose to submit in these forums, share in your profile, share in the resources you contribute, or otherwise disclose to the public areas on the site. We do not review, screen, or monitor the content you provide before you have uploaded it, and we will not delete any personal information that you upload to public areas of the Services.

 _Sharing with Social Networks_

We may allow you to share information with social networking websites, such as Facebook. We do not share your information with them unless you direct us to share it. Their use of the information will be governed by their privacy policies, and you may be able to modify your privacy settings on their websites.

 _Third Parties_

We will not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. Third parties are not authorized to access or collect our users’ personal information through the Services.

We may, however, share your personal information with the following categories of third parties: service providers that process payments or provide other services to help us develop, operate, and maintain the Services. We only authorize such entities to use your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and for no other purpose than to provide us necessary functions of the Services. If we find our service provides have misused our users’ data, we will take steps to have them delete your information.

 _Subsidiaries and Affiliates_

We do not share the information we collect with any subsidiaries or affiliates.

 _Our Commitment to Our Donors_

We will not sell, share, or trade our donor lists containing personal information, including names, email addresses, mailing addresses, and phone numbers, with any other non-affiliated organization for their own purposes, unless donors have given us specific permission to do so. This limitation includes personal information received online or offline by us from or about our donors in connection with requesting and/or processing donations. We will share information with service providers that will use the donors’ information only as necessary to provide their services to us.

 _Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement Requests; Protection of Our Rights_

We may disclose your information to a third party if (a) we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, (b) to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of service, (c) to protect the security or integrity of the Services, (d) to protect the property, rights, and safety of us, our users, donors, or the public from harm or illegal activities, (e) to respond to an emergency which we believe in the good faith requires us to disclose information to assist in preventing the death or serious bodily injury of any person, or (f) to investigate and defend ourselves or others against any third-party claims or allegations. In the event of a government or legal request for a user’s information, we will provide the user with notice so that they have an opportunity to seek a protective order or other legal remedy before we disclose the information.

 _Business Transitions_

In the event we go through a business transaction, such as a merger, acquisition by another entity, or bankruptcy, your information will likely be among the assets transferred. Please note that we will not provide notice, seek consent, or provide you with an option to delete your data before transferring your information in such an event. Any successor of a data transfer will be required to provide the same level of privacy protection described in this Privacy Policy.

 **Your Choices**

 _Deleting Your Information_

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire to use the Services, you may correct or update your profile by making the change on your profile, and you may delete or deactivate your profile by sending an email to privacy@curriki.org or by contacting us through any method described in the Curriki Contact Page. We will delete your information within 14 days after receiving and reviewing your request. Please note that we do not have a time-period after which we will automatically delete or limit the retention of any information after inactivity. Because your Contributions are connected to your Curriki account and we want to make as many Contributions as possible available through the Services, we will not delete your account or the personal information associated with it.

You can also choose which groups you would like to join, what members you would like to follow, and what mailings to receive. When you submit a resource to be included on the site, you can choose to share it publicly or privately, with only yourself or members of the group where you upload it. If you would like to delete a resource, you can email us at privacy@curriki.org.

 _Communications_

You can opt out of marketing messages and newsletter subscriptions by emailing us at [privacy@curriki.org](mailto:privacy@curriki.org) or by using the unsubscribe link included within each email. Even after you opt out from receiving promotional messages from us, you will continue to receive administrative messages from us.

 _Access and Third Party Sharing_

We currently do not provide an option for users to export or download all of the information Curriki receives from them. Nor do we provide authorized account managers or legacy contacts to access and download users’ data on their behalf.

As a matter of course, we do not provide users with a list of all of the personal information we share with third parties, however, you may write to us at privacy@curriki.org if you have questions about what personal information we share with third parties.

 **Other**

 _Children’s Privacy_

Curriki is not directed to children under 13. While a child under 13 is not technically constrained from creating an account, we don’t knowingly collect personal information from children under 13 online or offline or display advertisements to them. Similarly, we don’t obtain verifiable parental consent, provide parents with direct notice, or get their consent to use data for “internal operations” under COPPA. Because we don’t provide the Services to children under 13, we don’t restrict their purchases or activity on the Services or participate in any FTC safe harbor program.

If we find out that a child under 13 has given us personal information, we will take steps to delete that information. If you believe that a child under the age of 13 has given us personal information, please contact us at privacy@curriki.org. We will respond to all requests from parents, guardians, or others to prevent further collection of any child’s information.

 _Minors’ Privacy_

The Services are directed to adults such as educators and parents. That said, we do not constrain children between the ages of 13-18 from creating accounts. If they do so, we may collect personal information from them as described above.

 _Student Privacy_

Note that Curriki provides a way for educators and parents to share and access educational materials for K-12 school purposes. It does NOT collect student education records or students’ personal information. No such data is entered into Curriki’s Services. Thus, Curriki necessarily does not provide a way for students to review such information; does not take any steps to ensure the accuracy of such information; does not have a process for schools, parents, or students to modify such information; does not allow schools, parents, or students to submit requests to modify such information; and has no deadline for making such modifications. Similarly, there is no behavioral or contextual advertising based on student data and third parties cannot use such data to create profiles or otherwise use such data to target advertising to students, parents, teachers, or schools.

Given that we don’t collect student education records and we are not under the control of any educational institutions, we not provide additional information about FERPA rights. Likewise we do not disclose information as Directory Information under FERPA, disclose information pursuant to FERPA exceptions, or shift any liability or responsibility for parental consent to schools or districts.

 _Do Not Track_

We do not respond to “Do Not Track” signals from browsers, although you may disable tracking by managing the cookie settings in your browser. We have not signed any other privacy pledges or certifications.

 _International Users_

The Services are hosted in the United States and intended for users in the United States. If you access the Services from the European Union or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States for storage and processing. By providing your information you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please also note that this policy is not available in any other language besides English.

 _Security_

We provide reasonable security to protect the information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We use encryption to safeguard your data when it is in transit. We limit employee access to user information and we restrict access for unauthorized individuals to users’ data. Users are not required to use two-factor authentication to access their accounts.

No security measures are 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your data. We currently do not engage an auditor to review our privacy and security compliance. In the event of a security incident, we will provide users with notice consistent with applicable data breach notification laws.

 _Links to Other Websites_

Our Services may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. Please also be aware that because Curriki is not directed to children, we cannot guarantee whether links to outbound websites on the Services are age-appropriate for children. Third party websites linked to our Services may also use cookies and may track your activities across websites and over time. We encourage you read the privacy statements of these websites to learn more about how they collect, use, and share your information, including through the use of cookies

 _Changes to Our Privacy Policy_

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. You will have an opportunity to review any material changes to this policy at the time those changes become effective. If we make any material changes, we will notify you know through the Services, by email, or other communication. For example, if we change the context in which we collect your data, change our data collection practices, or if our practices become inconsistent with contractual requirements that we may have, we may make changes to this Privacy Policy, notify you, and obtain any required consent.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy periodically to stay up-to-date about our privacy practices. As long as you use the Services, you are agreeing to this Privacy Policy and any updates we make to it. You can always view previous versions of our Privacy Policy [here](https://www.curriki.org/privacy-policy-april-5-2016/).

 _Contact Us_

Feel free to contact us at any time with any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, changes to the policy, your personal information, our use and sharing practices, or your consent choices by emailing us at [privacy@curriki.org](mailto:privacy@curriki.org).
